Excuse me, sir. Good question for
you, man. Is this your cyber truck?
It is.
And what do you do for living out here in
Salt Lake City to be able to afford this car?
So, ultimately, I started in
the game of real estate and...
Entrepreneurship, man. I'm 36 years
old and I've built 35 companies.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
We've done over $600 million
in the last decade or so.
Over $10 million.
Eight figures. Clear $10 million.
How many companies do you own?
A lot.
How many?
I'd have to count them up, but several dozen.
I could start over today at a
job that pays me $3,000 a month,
and in less than a year, I
would be back to being a millionaire.
What is your net worth now?
Salt Lake City is home to some of
the most successful entrepreneurs in the entire world.
And today, we're going to be going
around the wealthiest parts of Salt Lake City
to ask some of these successful
business owners how they became wealthy
and how you can start your
path to becoming financially free in 2024.
So, with that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Salt Lake City
Totally broke. Came to Utah with $50.
So, how'd you turn $50 into $600 million?
Execution.
And I go all over the country just
asking business owners their advice to young entrepreneurs.
Is it cool if we ask
you a few questions for the channel?
Yeah, totally cool.
What was the best financial decision
that you made throughout your career?
Building the biggest Bitcoin mining
facility in Utah in 2014.
You built the biggest Bitcoin mining facility?
By mistake, because we're a computer company.
We were sitting on a bunch of video
cards, and we're like, well, let's hook them up.
And we started mining Bitcoin.
So, how long have you been in crypto for?
Since 2004.
Since 2013.
Is crypto the future of our economy?
I believe it's a big piece of it.
How so?
I believe the government is going
to release the central bank, digital currency,
and most real-world assets will all be tokenized.
And we've already seen this
with BlackRock starting to tokenize.
Have you ever met a billionaire before?
Yes, I have a few mentors that
are, and they've taught me the ways.
What was your lowest point
in your career as an entrepreneur?
I hired a very bad marketing manager, and
he lost $800,000 of my money in 90 days.
And this is when I didn't have a
lot, and it almost put me out of business.
How did you come back from that?
We had to lay off 75 people
because of that mistake that was made.
And so, what I did is got back to
basics, dotted all the I's, crossed all the T's,
hired great tax people, accountants, all
that, to look at all the books,
talked to mentors, framed it out, executed.
And within 12 months, we'd recovered.
And if you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
Absolutely.
How so?
Selling.
And how can somebody break
into the tech industry in 2024?
Well, when I started in the
early 90s, the internet was new,
and everybody thought it was a scam.
So, I embraced it because I thought a
lot of people would be getting on there,
and having problems they needed solved.
That same thing is going to
happen right now with blockchain and AI.
It's 1992 all the way again now.
So, that fresh opportunity is there
with undiscovered billions to be made.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you so much for your time.
I appreciate you.
So, my guy's done over $600
million over the last 10 years,
and he just dropped some amazing advice for you guys.
We're on our way to go get our next interview,
but I've got a very special announcement to make.
Next week, on June 4th, we're launching
the official School of Hard Knocks community.
Otherwise known as the School of Mentors.
In this community, you'll be able to hop
on live calls with 7, 8, and 9-figure entrepreneurs
to ask them questions about your
career, your life, and your business.
You'll be able to network with
and learn directly from these multi-millionaires
that we interview every single week.
You do not want to
miss out on any of this.
So, click the link down in the description
below to join the Hard Knocks community waitlist.
We'll see you on the inside
next week, but with that being said,
let's go get this next interview.
We are now in the
hidden hills of Salt Lake City
to interview one of the most
renowned entrepreneurs out here, Chris Krohn.
This guy has owned hundreds of millions of dollars,
businesses, and has done billions of
dollars in sales throughout his career.
We're here at his estate right
here out in Salt Lake City.
We're going to go throughout
what he was able to do
to become one of the
most successful entrepreneurs in the game.
Let's go see what he has to say.
What's up, guys? How are you doing?
Good to see you, man.
James?
Yes, sir.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
So, ultimately, I started in the game of real estate
and started with a small portfolio of 25 homes
that meant that when I graduated college,
I didn't need to get a job.
But then, from there, it turned into thousands of homes.
Thousands of homes.
Yeah.
So, how long have you been in real estate for?
20 years.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Clear $10 million.
Over $10 million.
And there's a big misconception in today's world
that you have to have a ton of
money to start creating wealth in real estate.
What would you say is that first move,
that first actionable step that somebody
can take in real estate today
to start generating some wealth?
I house hacked.
I mean, I put a 3%
down payment on my very first house,
bought it below market,
so that meant that I could strip the equity out,
and that house bought my next house
because about how I bought the second house,
that house bought my third house.
And that's how it erupted into a big portfolio.
And I just learned early on,
you actually don't need money,
credit to really transact real estate in high volume.
Are you a business owner?
Yeah.
How many companies do you own?
A lot.
How many?
I'd have to count them up, but several dozen.
What's the most common mistake
that you see business owners make
that prevents them from scaling and having that longevity?
They trust their accountants.
They trust their CFOs.
You're the CFO.
If you're the business owner,
the language of business is accounting,
which means you have to
learn to read your own financials.
You have to understand what a margin is.
You have to know what your gross revenue is.
You have to know what your expenses are.
And if you're trusting a controller or an accountant
to basically serve that up to you,
then you can be good at maybe making revenue,
but the reality is,
you're not going to keep very much of it
if you're trusting someone else
to help figure that component out for you.
So what is a lesson about money
that you would teach to somebody
that they won't learn in business school?
Financial arbitrage.
So the game is,
if I can borrow money
at 3% or 5% or 7%,
but I can earn 25%
or 50% or 100% on it,
all I'm really doing to build wealth
is I'm borrowing money at cheap rates,
and then I'm putting investments at high rates,
and I'm just the arbitrage is the delta.
It's the middle part.
That part's for me for being smart enough
to not trust other people with my money instead.
I can learn how to play that game.
And majority of Americans are living paycheck to paycheck.
From your perspective,
what keeps people broke in today's world?
They're taking advice from poor people.
Poor people are teaching poor people
how to become more poor.
And that's weird,
because they're like crabs in a bucket,
and they're basically pulling everyone down.
And that's the nightmare of the game.
You have to free yourself from that game.
And the number one fear,
when I really get down to it,
like what keeps people from jumping in
and finding a mentor
and making very different financial choices
and learning how to invest,
is they're afraid they're going to lose
their family and friends.
And the truth is, you will.
You will lose some of your family and friends.
They're going to say,
financially, that's too weird,
and that's too different.
But for every person you lose,
you're going to open up
into a whole new world of other people
that are going to inspire
even deeper greatness in you.
Hey, that was phenomenal, bro.
I appreciate you.
That was awesome, man.
So my guy Chris just dropped
some incredible advice
for all the young entrepreneurs out there,
but I've got another special surprise for you.
We are here at Keaton Hoskins' house.
Keaton has owned and operated
over 30 businesses over the last 20 years.
And we're here to get his secrets
on how he's became
one of the most successful entrepreneurs
in the entire country.
So with that being said,
come with me to see what Keaton has to say.
What industry did you decide
to pursue a career in?
Entrepreneurship, man.
I'm 36 years old
and I've built 35 companies
from the time I was 21.
So all the industries,
any industry I could start a business in,
that was the industry I was in.
What has been the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
This is going to sound really stupid,
but I don't know how much money
I've made in the last four years.
I don't, I mean,
I know that sounds really bad,
but I still currently,
I own four companies now.
I have no idea.
Over $10 million.
I can say that.
Yeah.
What's been the best financial advice
that you've ever received
throughout your career?
Two things.
I live and die by saying,
you should learn how to downgrade your lifestyle
so you can upgrade your life.
Most people live paycheck to paycheck.
One in four millionaires
still live paycheck to paycheck
because they refuse to downgrade
their lifestyle for a moment
so they can upgrade their life.
Now, if you decide to do that,
then my second piece of advice is
you should only dump money
into two things.
Personal investment
into you
and investing into your company.
That's it.
You shouldn't be spending money
anywhere else.
If it's not to help you grow
or your business grow,
you should not be spending money
until you have so much money
that you don't know what to do with.
The more money I put into me,
the more money I make.
The more money I put into my business,
the more money my business makes.
It's all about investing
into two things.
You and the business.
Let's talk about that a little bit
because a lot of people
don't make some money
and they'll instantly want to diversify
and jump from industry to industry.
How important for you
has it been becoming an expert,
the best in the world
at one thing
or just a few things?
As opposed to trying to diversify
and jump from industry to industry.
Dude, fuck diversifying.
Fuck portfolios.
Go deep.
That means find one thing
and go deep.
There's no person on this earth
that did 40 things
with a shotgun approach
and made a ton of money
in 40 different things.
They didn't do it.
Now, most people will tell you
that's what they're doing.
They're not.
They made their money
in one thing.
They found one thing
and they went hard as shit.
Everybody comes to me
and they're like,
hey, I got 100 grand.
I want to do stock market.
I want to do Bitcoin.
I want to start a business.
I want to buy a business.
I want to do this.
I want to...
No, no, no, no, no.
Find one thing
that you can get behind.
As human beings,
our capability is huge.
But at 20%
that I'm giving
to five different things,
I'll never be able
to reach anything
of significance
in those things.
If I put 100%
in one thing,
I'll crush that one thing.
Have you ever been broke before?
Honestly, no.
I mean, dude,
when I was 21,
I had 100 bucks
in my bank account.
When my father passed away,
I had 100 bucks
in my bank account.
That, I think,
is as broke as you can be.
And I just vowed
to my dad
that I would never
in my life
be in a place
where I needed somebody
to help me.
That's why I decided
I was going to build
everything on my back.
I've never been given money,
ever.
I've never had an investor
do something.
I mean, other than maybe
buying a house or a car,
I've never been given money.
So, I've never been broke
because I always knew
how to manage money.
I tell people this all the time.
If you can't manage $100,
you can't manage $100,000,
you can't manage a million.
Everybody says,
well, if I had more money,
I would do that.
No, you wouldn't.
You'd blow that shit
and you'd be living
paycheck to paycheck
even if you had $10 million.
So, for me,
I always lived by that
and I never wanted to be broke,
so I wasn't.
The majority of Americans
are living paycheck to paycheck
in today's world.
You even brought up
how one in four millionaires
are living paycheck to paycheck.
From your perspective,
what keeps people broke
in today's world?
They spend too much money
on shit that they don't need.
You don't need to do that.
Like, dude,
I hear people all the time,
the biggest problem
we have in our culture
right now is entitlement.
Everybody thinks
that they're owed something.
You're not owed shit.
No one's coming to save you.
Stop living this fucking life
that you think you deserve.
You don't deserve shit.
Dude, if I went back
and I had to make $3,000 a month,
I'm not kidding.
I would find four roommates,
a place that was
$1,000 a month.
We would split it.
I would be driving Uber
because I wouldn't have a car.
I would be riding my bike.
I would be cooking my meals.
I wouldn't be spending money
on anything.
I'd probably have
the same fucking outfit
every day
because I would stop
spending money on shit
that I don't need.
Dude, you've got people
in Africa wearing
the same clothes,
eating one meal a day.
They're not spending any money.
And you're telling me
you can't live like that?
That's garbage, dude.
You just think
because you live here
that you're owed the house
and the apartment
and the car
and the ring
and the watch.
That's bullshit.
You're not owed any of that.
You didn't earn it.
And until you earn it,
you can't have it.
My assistant,
he's from Mexico.
All the people,
usually,
that come across from Mexico,
they're the hardest workers.
You know why?
Because they're living
in dirt huts.
They have nothing.
They're not expected
to have anything.
They don't have
any entitlement.
They're here,
hey man,
I'm just here to fucking work.
I'm here to build something
and I'm trying to make
as much money as I can
so I can send it back
to my family.
For some reason,
people here in the United States
think that we're owed something.
We're not owed shit.
You are owed nothing
and your entitlement
is going to keep you broke
the rest of your life.
Oh my God, yo.
Wow.
That was phenomenal.
That's a wrap on today's video, guys.
Salt Lake City's got
some crazy business owners out here.
But I want you to like
and subscribe
for amazing content
coming very soon.
And as I said earlier
in this video,
next week on June 4th,
we're launching
the official School of Hard Knocks
community.
You do not want to miss out on this
because you'll be able to network
with the multi-millionaires
that we interview
every single week.
So click the link
in the description below
to join the Hard Knocks
community today.
We'll see you on the inside
next week.
And with that being said,
we'll see you in the next video.